minecraftskins.com 2018-11-22

# Privacy Policy

## Introduction

Your privacy is very important to us at The Skindex. To our best efforts, we have developed this Policy in order for you to understand how we collect, use, communicate, disclose and make use of personal information. The following outlines our privacy policy.

## Information collected

We will only retain personal information as long as necessary for the fulfillment of the service provided to you.

## Visitors

We log the IP addresses of visitors to help prevent malicious activities on our site.

## Members

We need your email and username (not your real name) to identify you as a unique individual when signing up.

Your email is also used to send you information such as your password recovery information and notification of events that are related to your account; such as comments, when some member you are following uploads a new skin, or when you have a new follower.

Your email notifications are enabled by default. You can choose to disable them [_here_](https://www.minecraftskins.com/settings/profile/).

We do not disclose your email address to 3rd parties unless required by law.

We do NOT recommend that you use your real name as your username. It is a violation of this privacy policy to reveal your identity in your username if you are located in the EEA.

Your IP address is logged for the sole purpose of moderation to prevent any abuse of services provided to you by this site. Only our administrators can view your IP address and it will not be shared with 3rd parties.

## Content and information submitted by you

We collect and store information you choose to provide to us when using our services. The information includes, posting of skins, comments, votes, ‘About Me’ in your profile page, skins added to your wardrobe, skins you downloaded, etc.

On your profile page other members or visitors will not be able to view your wardrobe, download history, who your followers are or who you are following. This information is only revealed to you during your logged-in session at our site.

Please do NOT reveal personal information about yourself or others such as phone numbers, addresses, birthdate, etc. anywhere on the site.

## Control, rights and correction of your data

As a member you can edit the title, description, tags of the skins that you had uploaded or delete them entirely at any time.

You can’t edit the contents of the comments you had posted but you are able to delete them at any time.

You can change your email address at any time but you will have to verify its validity every time you change it.

You can change your username (which is subjected to availability) but you are only allowed to do so once every 6 months. So, if you had just changed it, you will have to wait for 6 months before being able to change it again.

If you decide to delete your account, please contact us [_here_](https://www.minecraftskins.com/contact/). However please note that skin uploads and comments that you had made will remain visible to others unless you remove them on your own prior to the deletion of your account.

## Data Protection and Security

We take reasonable precautions to protect the data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction of the data. However, please exercise your due diligence by taking precaution on your end to protect any unauthorized entities from accessing your account at The Skindex.

## Age restrictions

Only users that are 13 years old or older are allowed to sign up for an account. Users residing in the EU have to be 16 years old or older.

## Ad partners and Analytics

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site.

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on this site send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

Exponential Interactive, Inc, our partner, have a legitimate interest to collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement. For more details including opt-out requests, access requests or complaints, please review their [_privacy policy_](http://exponential.com/privacy/) or contact their data protection officer via privacy@exponential.com.

We also use analytics partners such as Statcounter and Google Analytics, to help analyze usage and traffic for our services.

If you would like to know more information about these practices or do not want to provide information to these companies, please visit networkadvertising.org for more information for disable tracking.

## Change to this Privacy Policy

We may revise this privacy policy from time to time at our discretion to provide better clarity to our users and to coincide with the relevant laws and regulations.

## Contact Us

Please contact us [_here_](https://www.minecraftskins.com/contact/) if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy.
